Archives & Special Collections University of Nebraska–Lincoln Libraries
Carlton and Territa A. Lowenberg Collection on Emily Dickinson and Music
1988-1992
Lowenberg, Carlton
Lowenberg, Territa A.
19 boxes, 52 cassettes
Music MS 002
Formats:
Scores, cassette tapes
Restrictions:
No restrictions
Biographical Note
Carlton Lowenberg (1919-1996) spent years of his life collecting musical settings of poems by Emily Dickinson. He wrote to composers soliciting music and created the Emily Dickinson Music Society. Carlton Lowenberg wrote Musicians Wrestle Everywhere: Emily Dickinson and Music (Berkeley, California: Fallen Leaf Press, c1992).
Scope and Contents
The Carlton and Territa A. Lowenberg Collection on Emily Dickinson and Music consists of materials relating to musical settings of the poems of Emily Dickinson. It includes unpublished and published scores set to poems of Dickinson, correspondence with composers and publishers, programs, newspaper clippings, drafts of Lowenberg's book Musicians Wrestle Everywhere, correspondence about the Emily Dickinson Music Society, and cassette recordings containing performances of song settings of Emily Dickinson's poems.
Subjects:
Dickinson, Emily, 1830-1886 -- Musical settings; Dickinson, Emily, 1830-1886 -- Musical settings -- Bibliography; Lowenberg, Carlton -- Correspondence; Emily Dickinson Music Society; Songs
Series Description:
- Lowenberg Correspondence and Manuscripts, 1
  This includes correspondence between Carlton Lowenberg and Ann Basart of Fallen Leaf Press regarding the publication of Lowenberg's book Musicians Wrestle Everywhere: Emily Dickinson and Music. Additional materials associated with the book include manuscript drafts, reviews, and publicity materials. Other correspondence sent to and from Lowenberg includes that of numerous composers, listed alphabetically by last name. Lowenberg asks for copies of scores set to Dickinson's poetry and offers membership in the Emily Dickinson Music Society. Lowenberg also collected articles, theses, hymns, and catalogs related to musical settings of Dickinson's poetry.
- Ernst Bacon Correspondence and Works, 2
  Ernst Bacon (1898-1990) was an American composer, pianist, and conductor who composed over 250 songs over his career, including many set to poems by Dickinson. He was awarded three Guggenheim Fellowships and a Pulitzer Scholarship. Bacon's estate provided Lowenberg with copies of correspondence and documents related to his settings of Dickinson's poetry.
- Scores and Works, 3
  The majority of this series includes unpublished scores arranged alphabetically by last name of the composer. There are books that duplicate holdings in the Music Library. Additional scores are noted as oversized.
- Cassette Tape Recordings, 4
  This series consists of cassette recordings of musical settings of Dickinson's poetry. Some possible performers and performances are identified using Lowenberg, Musicians Wrestle Everywhere, even if not identified on the cassette tapes.
Container List:
- Lowenberg Correspondence and Manuscripts, 1
  - Correspondence, with Ann Basart, Fallen Leaf Press, 1989(?) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, with Ann Basart, Fallen Leaf Press, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, with Ann Basart, Fallen Leaf Press, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, with Ann Basart, Fallen Leaf Press, 1992(?) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Musicians Wrestle Everywhere, final draft (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Musicians Wrestle Everywhere, final draft, duplicate (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
  - Musicians Wrestle Everywhere, permission requests (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Musicians Wrestle Everywhere, publisher's refusals (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Musicians Wrestle Everywhere, kudos (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Musicians Wrestle Everywhere, illustrations (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Musicians Wrestle Everywhere, flyers (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Musicians Wrestle Everywhere, reviews (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, blind inquiries (about 55), 1989-1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, general inquiries, 1988-1992 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, library inquiries, 1989-1992 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, The Jones Library, Amherst, Massachusetts, Anne K. Williamson and Daniel Lombardo, 1979-1992 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, with scholars, 1989-1992 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, newsletter, and mailing lists, Dickinson Family Association, 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, University of Nebraska-Lincoln, Eva Sartori, Kent Hendrickson, and Stephen Hilliard, 1992-1993 RESTRICTED (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, with composers, A-B (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Robert Train Adams, Samuel H. Adler, Birgitte Alsted, Michael Anderson (no response), Michael Annicchiarico, Allyson Brown Applebaum, Elaine Barkin, James Beale, Stan Beckler, Brian Belet, Alan Belkin, Barnard Benoliel, Thomas Benjamin, Jean Berger, Marshall Bialosky, Herb Bielawa, Gordon Binkerd, Franceso Binni, Allan Blank, Howard Boatwright, Will Gay Bottje, Roger Bourland, Wolfgang Bottenberg, Lise Bro, Francis James Brown, Marilyn Bulli
  - Correspondence, with composers, C-F (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Ann Callaway, Philip Carlsen, Elliott Carter (via secretary), Niccolo Castiglioni, Robert Chauls, Henry Clarke (via Rory Karlsen), Robert Convery, Jean Coulthard, Charles Cushing (via Charlotte Cushing), Mark Dal Porto, Sharon Davis, Sarah Dawson, Ted Diaconoff, Emma Lou Diemer, Amadeo DeFilippi (no response), John Dowd, Charles Duncan, Michael Eckert, Bruce L. Faulconer, William Ferris, Vivian Fine, Burton Foreman, Donato Fornuto, Jack Fortner, Kenneth Fuchs
  - Correspondence, with composers, G (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Barbara Gibas, Paul Gibson, Gerald Ginsburg, Sylvia Glickman, Ernest Gold, Donald Grantham, Lita Grier
  - Correspondence, with composers, H (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Juliana Hall (via David Sims), John Harbison, David Harman, Roy Harris (through Dan Stehman), Kenneth Haxton, Irwin Heilner (via Florence Heilner), John Heiss, Eskil Hemberg, Michael Hennagin, Elizabeth Herberich, Carol Herman (no response), Harry Hewitt, Walter Hilse, Roy Hinkle, Samuel Hodges, Lee Hoiby, Erik Hojsgaard, William Holab, Lisbeth Holm, Derek Holman (via Margaret Holman), Michael Horvit, Mary Howe (via Dorothy Indenbaum), Richard Hundley
  - Correspondence, with composers, I-K (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Anthony Iannaccone, David Irving, Hunter Johnson, Joseph Jones, William Jordan (via Daniel Lombardo), Robert Jorvahl, Milan Kaderavek, Sergius Kagen (via Phoebe Castanis), Deborah Kavasch, Kevin Kelly, Linda Kernohan, Lee Kesselman, Leon Kirchner, Jerome Kitzke, Lothar Klein, Robert Kyr
  - Correspondence, with composers, L (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Ken Langer, Jules Langert, Borje Lardner, Alan Leichtling, David Leisner, Ludwig Lenel, Thomas T. Lenk, Fred Lerdahl, Frank Levy, Alan Lighty, Harris Lindenfeld, Dan Locklair, Ellen Jane Lorenz, Otto Luening
  - Correspondence, with composers, M-R (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Janice Macaulay, Giacomo Manzoni, Brian Marsh, Stephen Mayer, Ron McFarland, Henry Mollicone, Dorothy Rudd Moore, John Mueter, Bain Murray, John D. Niles, Roger Nixon, Lionel Nowak, Eldon Obrecht, David Olan, Esther Olin, Mollie O'Meara, Scott Pender, Sylvia Pengilly, Ronald Perera, George Perle, Brent Pierce (via Bernie Fisher), Daniel Pinkham, Paul Pisk, Charles W. Rasely, Elizabeth Raum, Robert Rericha, Marga Richter, Jay Rizzetto, Ned Rorem, Kenneth Rumery (no response), Charles H. Ruggiero
  - Correspondence, with composers, S (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Gerhard Samuel, Mark Saya, Thomas Schudel, C. M. Shearer, Clare Shore, Ann Silsbee, Faye-Ellen Silverman, Paul Siskind, Russell Smith, Randall Snyder, Edmund F. Soule, Elam Ray Sprenkle, Philip Springer, Robert Starer, Gitta Steiner, K. Marie Stolba, Steven Stucky, Morton Subotnick (via Kathleen Magee), William Sydeman
  - Correspondence, with composers, T-Z (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Louise Talma, Barry Taxman, Ludwig Tuman, Persis Vehar, Sean Vernon, George Walker, Joelle Wallach, Robert Ward, Betsy Frost Warren-Davis, James L. Waters, Ben Weber (via Matthew Paris), Mark Weber, Vally Weigl (via Rosalie Calabrese), Adolph Weiss (via William B. George), Nancy Wertsch (via John Lancaster), Andrew White, Beth Wiemann, Alec Wilder (via July Bell), Marilyn Ziffrin
  - Correspondence, with composers and others, Robert Baksa (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, with composers and others, Neely Bruce (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, with composers and others, Shirvani Chalayev (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, with composers and others, Gloria Coates (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, with composers and others, Aaron Copland (including 1979 letter to Ernst (Bacon?)) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, with composers and others, Gordon Getty (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, with composers and others, John Gould, musician (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, with composers and others, Richard Hoyt (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, with composers and others, Joseph Jones (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, with composers and others, Martin Kalmanoff (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, with composers and others, Roland Leich (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, with composers and others, Margaret Meachem (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, with composers and others, Marsha Marie Medley (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, with composers and others, Max Morath (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, with composers and others, Fred Morey, editor of Dickinson Studies (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, with composers and others, Alice Parker (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, with composers and others, Gerhard Pilz (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, with composers and others, Jo Ann Sims (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, with composers and others, Leo Smit (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, with composers and others, Frank E. Warren, Time and Eternity (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, with composers and others, Roger White, poet (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, with composers and others, Margaret Wood (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Article, Cluck, Nancy, Aaron Copland/Emily Dickinson Emily Dickinson Bulletin 32, 141-153 (photocopy), 1977 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Thesis, Cullen, Rosemary, Musical Settings of Emily Dickinson's Poetry Brown University, part 1 of 3, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Thesis, Cullen, Rosemary, Musical Settings of Emily Dickinson's Poetry Brown University, part 2 of 3, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Thesis, Cullen, Rosemary, Musical Settings of Emily Dickinson's Poetry Brown University, part 3 of 3, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Culbertson, Evelyn, with Carlton and Territa Lowenberg, 1988-1991 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Culbertson, Evelyn, materials on Arthur Farwell and Emily Dickinson, includes manuscript, and photograph and negative of Arthur Farwell (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Hovland, Michael, Musical Settings of Emily Dickinson Poems: a Bibliography, from Musical Settings of American Poetry: a Bibliography, incomplete pre-publication copy (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Farwell, Brice, with Carlton Lowenberg, 1981-1991 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Thesis, Moeller, Vernon Harold, Theoretical Aspects of Arthur Farwell's Musical Settings of Poems by Emily Dickinson University of Texas at Austin (ML410.F228 M7 1979) (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Article, Steinke, Stacie Columbo, Music Education for Women in Female Seminaries of the Nineteenth Century, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Sewell, Maryann S. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Article, correspondence, Tipton, Noel Hymns and Emily Dickinson: the Power of Melody, two versions (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Article, Wager, Inez, ED's Poems in Musical Settings (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, catalogs (2), American Composer's Alliance (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, membership materials, American Music Center, American Musicological Society, Sonneck Society, American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - American Composers Alliance (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, membership list, The American Society of Composers, Authors, and Publishers (ASCAP), 1989 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, BMI (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Dansk Musik Information Center (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, program, Emily Dickinson Center, Denmark (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Hymn Society of America,The Hymn, 1988, Oct., 1991, Oct. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Institute for Studies in American Music (I.S.A.M.), with Robert Schwarz (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Ernst Bacon, correspondence and works, 2
  - Ernst Bacon, correspondence, with Madi Bacon (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Lowenberg correspondence with Ellen (Bacon's wife) and Madi Bacon (Bacon's sister) regarding documents in his estate on Emily Dickinson settings.
  - Ernst Bacon, correspondence, with others, regarding Dickinson settings (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Ernst Bacon, articles, list of works, photograph (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Ernst Bacon, programs featuring Bacon's musical works (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Ernst Bacon, notices of manuscript for sale, The Postponeless Creature (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Ernst Bacon, newspaper clippings (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Ernst Bacon, Tributaries: songs by Ernst Bacon Berkeley, California: The Musical Offering, (2), c1978 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Ernst Bacon, The Songs of Ernst Bacon by John St. Edmunds, Poetry in Search of Music by Ernst Bacon, Sewanee, Tennessee, University Press, reprint from The Sewanee Review, 1941, Oct. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Ernst Bacon, Nature: Ten Songs for Chorus of Women's Voices, Soprano and Alto Soli, and Piano Boston, Mass., E.C. Schirmer Music Co., c1971 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Scores and Works, 3
  - Publications, catalog lists, composers' information (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Programs A-L, composers (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Programs M-Z, composers (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Reviews, composers (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper clippings, composers (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous music programs (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Performance flyers, brochures, programs, Carolyn Heafner (soprano) (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper clippings, gift of Roland Leich (composer) (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, nineteenth-century hymnals list, Philadelphia Rare Books and Manuscripts Company (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Documents, cassettes (2), A Musical Evening of Emily Dickinson Kimball Recital Hall, University of Nebraska-Lincoln (Also available in Performances from UNL's Glenn Korff School of Music), (http://collections.unl.edu/GKSoMPerformances.html), 1996, Nov. 24 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Membership correspondence, lists, Emily Dickinson Music Society (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Letter, Lowell Mason to Mary Lyon, on Lowell Mason papers at Yale (photocopy) (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Bibliography, Emily Dickinson's personal album of sheet music (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Carlton Lowenberg, Music want list, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Music catalogs (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous materials (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Published scores, duplicates in Music Library (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Incomplete scores (photocopies) (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Score, Twelve Poems of Emily Dickinson, set to music by Aaron Copland (photocopy) (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Score, Sound Forth Again the Nation's Voice: a New American Hymn words by Thomas Wentworth Higginson, music by C. Crozat Converse, Harper's Weekly, 1897, May 29 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Scores, Belet, Brian, Five Songs (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Scores, Bialosky, Marshall, four compositions (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Scores, Bialosky, Marshall, The Far Theatricals of Day (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Scores, Bottenberg, Wolfgang, Four Emily Dickinson Songs (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Scores, Bottje, Will Gay, Wayward Pilgrim (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Scores, Bruce, Neely, Emily's Flowers (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Scores, Chauls, Robert, Death is the Supple Suitor, Let Down the Bars, O Death (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Scores, Chauls, Robert, Songs of Great Men and Death (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Scores, Coates, Gloria There Breathed a Man, I Held a Jewel in My Fingers, A Word is Dead, In Falling Timbers Buried (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Scores, Convery, Robert, An Amethyst Remembrance early Dickinson settings, 1976-1980 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Scores, Dal Porto, Mark, Five Pieces for A Cappella Choir (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Scores, De Vries Robbé, Willem, Calendar (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Scores, Diacanoff, Ted, Songs of Transition and Passage (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Scores, Diacanoff, Ted, Two Poems of Death (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Scores, papers, Diemer, Emma Lou, There is a Morn by Us Unseen, Three Poems of Emily Dickinson (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Scores, Dowd, John, two songs (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Scores, Farwell, Arthur, collection of songs, quotation (some photocopies) (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Scores, Faulconer, Bruce, Five Poems of Emily Dickinson (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Scores, Foreman, Burton, Sweet is the Swamp, I Could Bring You Jewels, I Many Times Thought Peace Had Come (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Scores, Fortner, Jack, three songs (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Scores, Freed, Isadore, Chartless (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Scores, letters, Fuchs, Kenneth, Three Poems of Emily Dickinson (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Scores, Gould, John A., arrangement, five songs (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Scores, Green, Ray, Concluded Lives (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Scores, Harris, Roy, Read Sweet, How Others Strove (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Scores, Herberich, Elizabeth, Four Poems of Emily Dickinson (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Scores, Hilse, Walter, Nine Dickinson Songs, I Started Early (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Scores, Hinkle, Roy B., About God, Love, and Nature (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Scores, Højsgaard, Erik, Variations: Six Songs of Autumn, Two Songs for Mixed Choir (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Scores, Howe Mary, Three Emily Dickinson Pieces (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Scores, Hoyt, Robert, collected songs (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Scores, Hundley, Richard, Will There Really be a Morning (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Scores, Johnson, Hunter, three songs (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Scores, Johnson, Lockrem, A Letter to Emily, libretto (not Dickinson poetry) (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Scores, Jones, Joseph, songs (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Scores, Jordahl, Robert, Death and the Maiden (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Scores, Kalmanoff, Martin, If I Can Stop One Heart from Breaking, 20 songs (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Scores, Kelly, Kevin, There's a Certain Slant of Light (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Scores, Kent, Frederick James, Women's Voices (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Scores, Kesselman, Lee R., Buzzings: Three Pieces for Mixed Chorus, Libera Me: Requiem for Three Poets (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Scores, score samples, Klein, Lothar (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Scores, Kyr, Robert, Maelstrom, Toward Eternity (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Scores, Langer, Ken, ten songs (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Scores, letter, Lardner, Börje, There's a Certain Slant of Light, and songs set to poems of Philip Freneau and Ralph Waldo Emerson (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Scores, Leich, Roland, Color, Caste, Denomination (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Scores, Leich, Roland, Forty-Seven Emily Dickinson Songs (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Scores, Lenel, Ludwig, Five Poems by Emily Dickinson (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Scores, Lockwood, Normand, Three Verses of Emily Dickinson (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Scores, Lorenz, Ellen Jane, Bring Me the Sunset in a Cup (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Scores, Morath, Max, In Separate Rooms (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Scores, Mueter, John, It Is a Lonesome Glee (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Scores, Nowak, Lionel, Three Dickinson Songs (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Scores, Parker, Etta, Have You Got a Brook (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Scores, Pengilly, Sylvia, Three Poems of Emily Dickinson (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Scores, Pilz, Gerhard, The Brain is Wider than the Sky (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Scores, Pinkham, Daniel, Down an Amherst Path (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Scores, Raum, Elizabeth, The Passing (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Scores, Rericha, Robert J., There's a Certain Slant of Light (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Scores, Richter, Marga, Three Songs to Poems of Emily Dickinson (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Scores, Samuel, Gerhard, Three Dickinson Songs (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Scores, Saya, Mark, Three, by Emily (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Scores, Seeboth, Max, I Never Saw a Moor (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Scores, programs, Sims, Jo Ann, That I Did Always Love (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Scores, Siskind, Paul, I'm Nobody; I Have No Life but This (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Scores, Smit, Leo, three songs (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Scores, South, Jean and Roger White, One Bird, One Cage, One Flight: Homage to Emily Dickinson, music, Jean J. South, words, Roger White (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Scores, Springer, Philip, Come Slowly, Eden (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Scores, Starer, Robert, three songs for chorus (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Scores, Stucky, Stephen, Two Poems of Emily Dickinson (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Scores, Tipton, Noel, Three Songs (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Scores, Walker, Christopher, Hope is the Thing with Feathers (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Scores, Wallach, Joelle, Of Honey and of Vinegar (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Scores, Wilder, Alec, Five Songs (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Scores, Wilder, Alec, I Hide Myself (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Published book, A Guide to the Music of Arthur Farwell and to the Microfilm Collection of his Work / a centennial commemoration prepared by his Children edited by Brice Farwell, New York, Briarcliff Manor, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Published book, Lowenberg, Carlton, Musicians Wrestle Everywhere: Emily Dickinson & Music Berkeley, California, Fallen Leaf Press, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Published book, Culbertson, Evelyn Davis, He Heard America Singing: Arthur Farwell, Composer and Crusading Music Educator Metuchen, New Jersey, The Scarecrow Press, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Published book, Dickinson, Clarence, The Technique and Art of Organ Playing New York, The H.W. Gray Co., 1922 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Emily Dickinson music (EDM) discs, box 1 of 3, seventeen 5 ¾" floppy discs (Box 17, Box 1)
  - EDM discs, box 2 of 3, thirteen 5 ¾" floppy discs (Box 17, Box 2)
  - EDM discs, box 3 of 3, eight 5 ¾" floppy discs (Box 17, Box 3)
  - EDMS discs, six 5 ¾" floppy discs (Box 17, Box 4)
  - CL ED MUSIC, EDM SETT discs, four 5 ¾" floppy discs (Box 17, Box 5)
  - Microfilm, misc. bound volume of music with Emily Dickinson' signature. Original in Houghton Library (Box 17, Box 6)
  - Oversize scores, Bacon, Ernst, Nature (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Oversize scores, Benoliel, Bernard, Eternity-junctions (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Oversize scores, Beckler, Stanworth, Five Poems of Dickinson, Four Short Poems of Emily Dickinson, Man and Divers Bestiall Companions (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Oversize scores, Biscardi, Chester, The Gift of Life (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Oversize scores, Bialosky, Marshall, Birds, Bees, and Butterflies (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Oversize scores, Bourland, Roger, A Slash of Blue, Dickinson Madrigals (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Oversize scores, Coulthard, Jean, Five Love Songs for Baritone (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Oversize scores, Getty, Gordon, White Election (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Oversize scores, Ginsburg, Gerald, selection of his best (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Oversize scores, Hemberg, Eskil, Love Fancies (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Oversize scores, Lighty, Alan K., Music from Amherst (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Oversize scores, Mayer, Stephen, Six Poems of Emily Dickinson (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Oversize scores, brochures, programs, McFarland, Ron, A Dickinson Dialogue, Emily Dickinson's American Garden Song Book (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Oversize scores, brochure, program, Parker, Alice, Echoes from the Hills, Three Seas (Box 19, Folder 5)